{"Topic": "Plants and Trees (3 pages)", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "Trees are leafless for a shorter or longer season of the year in", "op1": "Evergreen forest", "op2": "Mangrove forest", "op3": "Scrub Jungle forest", "op4": "Deciduous forest", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Oxygen liberated during photosynthesis is coming from", "op1": "Carbon dioxide", "op2": "Water", "op3": "Break down of chlorophyll", "op4": "Atmosphere", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Stilt roots are found in -", "op1": "Banyan", "op2": "Maize", "op3": "Mango", "op4": "China rose", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "With which one of the following is Dalbergia species associated?", "op1": "Walnut", "op2": "Sandalwood", "op3": "Teak", "op4": "Rosewood", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which one of the following parts of the pitcher plant becomes modified into a pitcher?", "op1": "Leaf", "op2": "Flower", "op3": "Fruit", "op4": "Flower bud", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "The age of a tree can be determined more or less accurately by", "op1": "finding the ratio of height to the width of the tree", "op2": "counting the number of rings in the trunk", "op3": "measuring the height of the tree", "op4": "measuring the diameter of the trunk", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "What type of roots are the hanging structures in a banyan tree?", "op1": "Buttress roots", "op2": "Storage roots", "op3": "Stilt roots", "op4": "Prop roots", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Fruits of this plant are found underground -", "op1": "Potato", "op2": "Carrot", "op3": "Groundnut", "op4": "Onion", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which one of the following areas is noted for mangrove vegetation?", "op1": "Lava forest of Kalimpong", "op2": "Sajnekhali forest of South 24 Parganas", "op3": "Dandakaranya forest of Orissa", "op4": "Corbet National Park of U. P.", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which of the following is the tallest perennial grass?", "op1": "Nile grass", "op2": "Paddy plant", "op3": "Sugarcane", "op4": "Bamboo", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following is not a root?", "op1": "Potato", "op2": "Carrot", "op3": "Radish", "op4": "Turnip", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Cotton fibre is obtained from which part of the plant?", "op1": "Flowers", "op2": "Fruit", "op3": "Seed", "op4": "Leaves", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Certain parts of a plant can be bent easily without breaking. This flexibility in certain parts, like leaf and stem, can be attributed to the abundance of", "op1": "parenchyma", "op2": "collenchyma", "op3": "sclerenchyma", "op4": "xylem and phloem", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which of the following is not a micronutrient for a plant?", "op1": "Iron", "op2": "Magnesium", "op3": "Molybdenum", "op4": "Manganese", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "The common edible mushroom is a", "op1": "mass of fungal spores", "op2": "type of hypha", "op3": "tightly packed mycelium", "op4": "structure used for producing asexual spores", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "The main function of the inner bark of a woody plant is to", "op1": "transport minerals and water from the roots to the leaves", "op2": "act as a membrane impermeable to water and gas", "op3": "transport food from the leaves to the other parts of the plant", "op4": "protect the plant from herbivorous animals", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Sandalwood tree is considered a", "op1": "total root parasite", "op2": "total stem parasite", "op3": "stem parasite", "op4": "partial root parasite", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Biological catalysts in living organisms are known as", "op1": "hormones", "op2": "vitamins", "op3": "steroids", "op4": "enzymes", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which of these trees do not have annual growth rings?", "op1": "Banyan trees", "op2": "Oaks", "op3": "Palm trees", "op4": "Pine trees", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which one of the following types of plants produces spores and embryo, but without seeds and vascular tissues?", "op1": "Gymnosperms", "op2": "Pteridophytes", "op3": "Bryophytes", "op4": "Angiosperms", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which among the following is not a true fruit?", "op1": "Apple", "op2": "Date", "op3": "Grape", "op4": "Plum", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Xerophytes thrive in", "op1": "hot and arid condition", "op2": "cool and wet condition", "op3": "hot and wet condition", "op4": "cool and arid condition", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Biodiversity is highest in", "op1": "Tundra zone", "op2": "Prairie zone", "op3": "Temperate zone", "op4": "Tropic zone", "Answer": 3}]}